{
  "quiz": [
    {
      "category": "Geography",
      "id": "1",
      "correctAnswer": "Portugal",
      "incorrectAnswers": ["Kosovo", "Cuba", "Panama"],
      "question": "Lisbon is the capital city of which country?"
    },
    {
      "category": "Society & Culture",
      "id": "2",
      "correctAnswer": "Disneyland",
      "incorrectAnswers": ["Hallmark", "Holiday Inn", "Airbnb"],
      "question": "Which brand is associated with the marketing slogan 'The happiest place on earth'?"
    },
    {
      "category": "Society & Culture",
      "id": "3",
      "correctAnswer": "Moses",
      "incorrectAnswers": ["Mohammed", "Frodo", "Buddha"],
      "question": "Who of these was a key figure of Jewish/Christian history?"
    },
    {
      "category": "Science",
      "id": "4",
      "correctAnswer": "myths",
      "incorrectAnswers": ["mountains and their mapping", "character", "sex"],
      "question": "What is Mythology the study of?"
    },
    {
      "category": "Film & TV",
      "id": "5",
      "correctAnswer": "\"With great power comes great responsiblity.\"",
      "incorrectAnswers": [
        "\"I love lamp.\"",
        "\"Which would be worse, to live a monster or die as a good man?\"",
        "\"La-dee-da, la-dee-da.\""
      ],
      "question": "Which of these quotes is from the film 'Spider-Man'?"
    },
    {
      "category": "Society & Culture",
      "id": "6",
      "correctAnswer": "38th President of the USA. ",
      "incorrectAnswers": [
        "Developed the world's first vaccine (for smallpox).",
        "Italian explorer who landed in America.",
        "Dictator of Nazi Germany."
      ],
      "question": "Which of the following describes John F. Kennedy?"
    },
    {
      "category": "Science",
      "id": "7",
      "correctAnswer": "Dialects",
      "incorrectAnswers": ["X-Rays", "Drugs", "Clouds"],
      "question": "What is dialectology the study of?"
    },
    {
      "category": "Music",
      "id": "8",
      "correctAnswer": "Michael Jackson",
      "incorrectAnswers": ["Nicki Minaj", "Neil Young", "Eric Clapton"],
      "question": "Which musician released the album 'Off the Wall'?"
    },
    {
      "category": "Geography",
      "id": "9",
      "correctAnswer": "London",
      "incorrectAnswers": ["Manchester", "Birmingham", "Winchester"],
      "question": "What is the capital city of The United Kingdom?"
    },
    {
      "category": "Science",
      "id": "10",
      "correctAnswer": "Erosion",
      "incorrectAnswers": ["Sediment", "Vegetation", "Sublimation"],
      "question": "By what process is rock worn down by the weather?"
    },
    {
      "category": "Society & Culture",
      "id": "11",
      "correctAnswer": "Nike",
      "incorrectAnswers": ["Reebok", "Adidas", "Puma"],
      "question": "Which brand is associated with the marketing slogan 'Just do it'?"
    },
    {
      "category": "Science",
      "id": "12",
      "correctAnswer": "primates",
      "incorrectAnswers": [
        "the attribute (of a word) of being self descriptive",
        "the heart",
        "the study and design of machines at the molecular level"
      ],
      "question": "What is Primatology the study of?"
    },
    {
      "category": "Geography",
      "id": "13",
      "correctAnswer": "Perth",
      "incorrectAnswers": ["Auckland", "Christchurch", "Queenstown"],
      "question": "Which of these cities is in Australia?"
    },
    {
      "category": "Arts & Literature",
      "id": "14",
      "correctAnswer": "J. K. Rowling",
      "incorrectAnswers": [
        "Christopher Tolkien",
        "Philip Pullman",
        "C. S. Lewis"
      ],
      "question": "Which author wrote 'Harry Potter and the Half-Blood Prince'?"
    },
    {
      "category": "Society & Culture",
      "id": "15",
      "correctAnswer": "Motorola",
      "incorrectAnswers": ["Sony", "Samsung", "Nokia"],
      "question": "'Hello Moto' is a slogan associated with which communications brand?"
    },
    {
      "category": "Arts & Literature",
      "id": "16",
      "correctAnswer": "J. K. Rowling",
      "incorrectAnswers": [
        "Christopher Tolkien",
        "Philip Pullman",
        "C. S. Lewis"
      ],
      "question": "Which author wrote 'Harry Potter and the Philosopher's Stone'?"
    },
    {
      "category": "Geography",
      "id": "17",
      "correctAnswer": "Germany",
      "incorrectAnswers": ["Ukraine", "Poland", "Switzerland"],
      "question": "Berlin is the capital city of which country?"
    },
    {
      "category": "Sport & Leisure",
      "id": "18",
      "correctAnswer": "Football",
      "incorrectAnswers": ["Athletics", "Motor racing", "Basketball"],
      "question": "With which sport is Pele associated?"
    },
    {
      "category": "Science",
      "id": "19",
      "correctAnswer": "the climate",
      "incorrectAnswers": [
        "fossils of ancient life",
        "glaciers",
        "a branch of medicine that deals with the venous system"
      ],
      "question": "What is Climatology the study of?"
    },
    {
      "category": "Film & TV",
      "id": "20",
      "correctAnswer": "\"You're gonna need a bigger boat.\"",
      "incorrectAnswers": [
        "\"A census taker once tried to test me. I ate his liver with some fava beans and a nice Chianti.\"",
        "\"Wait a minute, wait a minute. You ain't heard nothin' yet!\"",
        "\"Mother of mercy, is this the end of Rico?\""
      ],
      "question": "Which of these quotes is from the film 'Jaws'?"
    }
  ]
}
